Vernon Briggs Publications /4236 PUBS
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Vernon Briggs Publications
1965-2012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Briggs, Vernon M.
/4236 PUBS
4.5 cubic feet
4.5 linear ft.
Publications (documents).
8311144
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 10, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 05, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Vernon M. Briggs, Jr. is Emeritus Professor of Labor Economics, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University. He received his B.S. degree in economics from the University of Maryland and his M.A. and Ph.D. degrees in economics from Michigan State University. Before coming to Cornell in 1978, he taught at the University of Texas at Austin for 14 years.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4236: Vernon Briggs Files
Briggs, Vernon M.
8311144
- The Mutual Aid Pact of the airline Industry, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  ILRR October
- Strike Insurance Plan of the R.R Industry, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  IR February
- Negro Participation in Apprenticeship Programs, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  JHR Winter
- Remedies for Discrimination in Apprenticeship Programs, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  IR May
- Negroes in Apprenticeship, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  US DOL Monograph #6 September
- Manpower Programs and Regional Development, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  MLR March No.3
- Administration of Training Programs-Joint Economic Committee 3, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Report of the Commission on Civil Disorders, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  JEI June
- Testimony before Mass Advisely Commodlee of U.S Commission or Civil Rights, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  June Boston
- The Negro in American Industry, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  JHR Summer
- They have the power-- We have the people, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  EEOC- June
- The Negro in American Industry: Review of Seven Studies, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Summer
- Report of the Commission on Civil Disorders- A Review Article, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- National Manpower Policy, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Negro Employment in the Houston Labor Market, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Chicano & Rural Poverty & Human Resource Abstract, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  March
- Emergency Employment Act: Texas Experience, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- U.S. Mexico Border Policies & Chicano Welfare, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  April
- Texas Law Review (boot reviews), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  August
- The Emergency Employment Act of 1971: Reprint of 1st Draft (Box 1, Folder 20)
- of Manpower Programs for Chicanos January, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Emergency Employment Act in Texas Comment of LBJ School, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  May
- Emergency Employment Program in Texas September, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Mexico-US Border: Public Policy & Chicano Economic Welfare - January, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Texas Emergency Employment Act of 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- The "New Immigration" and the Presumptions of Social Policy Michael J. Piore (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Opening Skilled Crafts (Review), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  ILRR
- Migration of Mexican Nationals into US-Mounting Issues -70s, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Employment Discrimination & Labor Market Policies February, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- National Academy of Sciences Labor Force Segments, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Employment & Income of Black Americans Career Behavior Sp., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Houston Chronicle Article Feb 16, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Illegal Immigration & American Labor Force: Use "Soft" Data For Anal April, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Mexican Immigration & Labor Force- Texas Business Review April, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Mexican workers in US Labor Market - November, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  #85
- Starr County: A Brief Description D.O.L Spring, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Mexican Americans Tomorrow (Review), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  MLR July
- Illegal Aliens: Restrictive Border Policy, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  December #85
- Illegal Immigration & American labor force: Use soft data for analogue, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Railroad brotherhoods dictionary of American History July, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Issues in full employment: Immigration August, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Illegal Immigration: Threat and Challenge April, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Welfare reform in rural south- December, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Problem of illegal immigration, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- OICS: Community based Manpower, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  ILRR January review
- Labor market aspects Mexican migration to U.S., 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Welfare reform and the plight of the poor in the rural south, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Monthly labor review
- Human needs and income supplements programs, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  November
- Wage and occupational differences-July, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Mexican Illegal Immigration (review), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  ILRR July
- Impact of undocumented worker on the labor market 1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Special labor market segments, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Quest of enforceable immigration policy thrust, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  JEPT fall
- PSE in rural south, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  IRRA December
- Biligual education, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  September 28
- Bilingual education Texas observer, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  December
- Book Review Fernandez- US Mexican Border, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  IMR Fall
- How well do you speak Spanish? Buffalo courier-express, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Letter to editor Cornell Sun, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Youth employment programs in S.W. Texas review 6, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Unemployment & Underemployment in rural areas- University of North Carolina press, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Democracy Authority and Alienation Review, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Foreign labor-Dissenting view-working paper, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Illegal Immigration: Continuing Issue for 1980s- Bell Journal, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Economic development in south- Growth $ Change, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Employment & Income in SW in 1980s, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Adherent
- Comparative Metropolitan Complex Review, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  ILRR April
- Select Commission: Critique- Texas bus review, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  January
- PSE: Lessons for 1980s, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  IRRA
- Illegal Immigration-- Mexico ILR Report, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Nonimmigrant labor policy: Future trend or abberation?, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Affirmative action and Tenure, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Hamilton S.-Apprenticeship as a transition to adulthood in W.Germany, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- ILR Voice-Immigration Policy, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  October
- JEI- Nonimmigrant in Labor policy in U.S, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  September
- IRRA Discussion, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- HR Roundtable, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- TVA And the JOBS bill, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- The Simple truth- The Texas observer, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Briggs, V-Method of analysis of illegal immigration into U.S, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  ILR Press
- Studies in international Labour Migration, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  September review
- Interregional Migration, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  June review
- For We Are Sold, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  Review ILRR October
- Immigration Policy for today, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  Bus Forum
- The "Albatross" of Immigration Reform: Winter, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Canadian Immigration Reports, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- The growth and composition of the US Labor force, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Unfinished Agenda-Immigration Human Resource Executive, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- H.R. Development JEI, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Youth employment & Training programs, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Immigration Reform & the urban labor market, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Editorial to New York times, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  January 12
- Purpose of legal immigration in 1990s and beyond June 10 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- McAdams, A.- the Computer industry, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Efficiency and Equity Goals.Population and Environment., 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Political Confront NPG, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Labor Force Changes AFL-CIO, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- V. Briggs "Immigrant workers" (Forum) BNA's employees relation Weekly, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Review of Industries, Films and Jobs in Social Forces, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Scope Review of Friends or Strangers, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Lozano Beverly Review ASQ, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Briggs, V.B., Jr "A special section for correspondence $ cont.", 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Daly and Cobb review, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Review of Culbertson PSE, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Public Policies in rural communities, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- BNA employee relations immigration and skilled shortages, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Employer sanction and discrimination, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  IMR
- Comments on urban institute of study of employers sanction, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- NPA workforce and immigration policy, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- IRRA immigration reform and urban labor forces, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Immigration Policy: Political or economic challenge, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Unions under siege (book review) JEI, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Immigration act of 1990 P&E Fall 1991 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Strengths at the gate: New York Times, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  October 6
- Borjas Review P& E, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Mexican Free trade, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- LA Riot and Immigration scope 1992 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Immigration reform and economy New York Times, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- JEI Book Review Solow, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Winter
- CAHRS: Immigration Policy- Gone Awry, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Policy Dilemmas in urban education of urban affairs, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Veblen commons award to Ray Marshall (Introduction) JGI, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Dillard Memorial JEI, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Immigration Policy: Tool of Labor Economics levy Institute, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Dead emerald sheet: Female Immigration & Daycare childcare action news, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Immigrant Labor & 'dirty' work P& E, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  July
- Union- Undocumented Study Proposal Material, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Report-Levy institute interview, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Immigration: Neglected Policy Background, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Administration of Immigration policy social content 6, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- International Labor migration and labor mobility: The Receiving Countries, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Mass Immigration free trade & the forgotten worker CMS vol XVII, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Forum Mass Immigration and urban underclass, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Mass Immigration and free trade challenge, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Achieving national eco goal and immigration Policy CAHR, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- UNZ vs Them: immigration Policy review, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  winter
- Washington Times Letter to editor, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Anatomy of reform (review) ASQ, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Immigration Policy & U.S. Economy JEI, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- International Labor Mobility: The receiving countries, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Review of case against immigration, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Neely Review, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Achieving Economical and Social Goals of heart and mind Levitan, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Ethics Trumping Social Contract, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Training Disadvantages, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- American Mosaic, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  IMR- Summer
- "Wrong Data" National review, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Institutional Barriers to full employment EAEPE Management Athens, Greece, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Income Disparity & Unionism: Workplace interferences of immigration NPA, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- "Error in unemployment rate", 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  Immigration review no.30 (1997:Fall/1998:Winter)
- Texas Observer corrected census, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  October 9
- Review "Immigrants out" Journal of American ethnic history, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Sumer
- American-style Capitalism of income disparity: Prospects for anarchy JEI, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  June
- Malthus: The Economist Social Contract, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Threat to low skilled CAHRS working paper, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- immigration policy and the plight of unskilled workers, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- JEI Review of ethnic economics & public policy, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Testimony U.S. House of representatives, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Immigration and poverty Proceedings, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Economic Contributions of Henry George Encyclopedia of political economy 1999 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Reigning in U.S Miami Law School, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Reigning in Rogue Policy CAHRS paper, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Immigration and Human Resource Development HR spectrum, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Plight of unskilled social contract, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  (reprint of
- Reigning in rogue policy Interamerican Law review, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Winter- Spring
- Annals of AAPSS, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Review of Reimershook
- Veto HIB: Ithaca Journal, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Labor day September 4
- Youth workers (review), 2000 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Review of Bhagwadis Stream of Windows in Journal of Policy analysis and management, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Immigration Economics New York times, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Blueprints for Ideal legal immigration policy, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  CIS
- American unionism and Immigration Policy, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  CIS Background August
- Immigration Harms workers S.D Union, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  September 2
- Crossroads: Immigration Policy and American unionism, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Social Contract March
- U.S Population & Labor force: Incongruity, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Letter to Texas observer, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Review: Massey's Mexican Migration, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Poverty and Immigration JEI, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- "Economic Well being of black Americans the overarching influence of U.S immigration policies", 2003 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  Review of black political Economy
- Book Review: D. King Making American Law History, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Testimony: Immigration Policy & Low wage workers: Influence union House of representatives, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Testimony: U.S Senate, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  February 12
- Guest workers and jobless rates, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  Boston globe
- Guest workers, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  Background CIS
- "Immigrant & Unionism: Reality check" the future of American unionism, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Economic well being of black Americans: Immigration Impact, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  Shulman editor
- Book review: Science at the borders, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  ILRR Review- October
- Immigration policy and poverty social contract, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  Reprint
- Immigration Rogue LM policy perspectives on work, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  IRRA summer
- Impact brief: Guest workers, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Doomed to fail: Guest worker program policy brief, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Immigration "Redux" Texas observer, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Immigration and Income disparity ethics of immigration policy, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Parting shots: Immigration, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  Yale economical review
- Testimony: Immigration reform and labor force judiciary committee U.S House of representatives, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Living standards of scarce reserves and immigration policy- Interview, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  Social contract- summer
- Administration of immigration policy revisited, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  Social contract
- Farm workers shortage myth, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  Ithaca Journal
- Immigration reform: Enforcement voices Immigration Issue, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  Cornell University
- Review: Milkman's LA Story, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  ILRR review
- Testimony: Real immigration reform House of representatives, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  May 3
- Review: Blacks organized labor, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  EH. Net
- Testimony: Immigrant organized labor judiciary Human Resource, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Revisiting the administration of immigration policy social contract, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Immigration policy and organized labor, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  (Reprint in social contract)-summer
- State of U.S. immigration policy relevance of therapy and data, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- IMM policy: Fundamentals labor law, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Illegal immigrants and black workers U.S. civil rights commission, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  April 4
- Immigration policy in free societies- Principal vs political Fraser institute conference Montreal CA, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  June 4
- Illegal Immigration Stanford review, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Illegal Immigration, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  Summer-(reprint of Stanford review)
- Jordan Commission: A Beacon, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  Writers Workshop
- Report of CIR, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  Jordan Commission PEIR Spring
- Immigration Policy and free societies, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  Fraser Institute
- State of U.S. Immigration Policy" Journal of law economical and political", 2009 (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Illegal immigration and immigration reform, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  Connecticut public interest law journal
- Economic downturn: Labor Deficiencies of immigration policy, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Economic downturn U.S Immigration Policy, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 68)
- Elusive goal Immigration reform Journal policy analysis management, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  Fall